A story of civilized disobedience
Tea with Mussolini is a comedy, drama, war film directed by Franco Zeffirelli.
In 1930s fascist Italy, adolescent Luca just lost his mother.
His father, a callous businessman, sends him to be taken
care of by British expatriate Mary Wallace.
Mary and her cultured friends - including artist Arabella, young widow Elsa,
and archaeologist Georgie - keep a watchful eye over the boy.
But the women's cultivated lives take a dramatic turn when
Allied forces declare war on Mussolini.
Lady Hester Random, played by Maggie Smith.
Arabella, played by Judi Dench.
Mary Wallace, played by Joan Plowright.
Elsa Strauss-Almerson, played by Cher.
Georgina "Georgie" Rockwell, played by Lily Tomlin.
Luca, played by Baird Wallace.
Tea with Mussolini (Italian: Un tè con Mussolini) is a 1999 semi-autobiographical comedy-drama war film directed by Franco Zeffirelli, scripted by John
Mortimer, telling the story of a young Italian boy's upbringing by a circle of British and American women before and during the Second World War.
At the 53rd British Academy Film Awards, Tea with Mussolini won the BAFTA
Award for Best Actress in a Supporting Role (Maggie Smith).
The film also nominated for BAFTA Award for Best
Costume Design but lost to Sleepy Hollow.
The film explores themes of hotel, ambassador, loss of loved one, italy, widow.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.